George M. Gray Museum Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
George M. Gray Museum Archives
1963-1994
IZAR.002021
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
21
Archives of the George M. Gray Museum and Systematic Ecology Program.
Gray Museum, Marine Biological Labaratory
Biographical Sketch
The George M. Gray Museum traces its beginnings to material that originated from the Supply Department of the Marine Biological Laboratory. The museum is named for George Gray, an early collector in the Supply Department who spent time curating the preserved specimens. The collection developed slowly, but underwent rapid expansion after the transfer of specimens from the Systematics Ecology Program.
The Marine Biological Laboratory Systematics Ecology Program was founded by Carriker in 1963 to study the flora and fauna of the western North Atlantic. The invaluable reference manual Keys to Invertebrates of the Woods Hole Region was published in 1969. Subsequently, as an outgrowth of this manual, a series focusing on taxonomy was published as National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration Technical Reports under the subseries title Fauna and Flora of the Eastern (originally Northeastern) United States.
The George M. Gray Museum collection complements the Division?s extensive holdings of invertebrates from the same region assembled and studied by Addison E. Verrill and his colleagues during the latter half of the 19th century, partially as a result of his association with the U.S. Fish Commission. Many of the New England localities studied by the Fish Commission were ultimately resurveyed by the Systematics Ecology Program?s dredging operations nearly 100 years later. The combination of these 2 collections is a unique resource that will help document historical faunal changes in New England.
Description of the Material
These archives include labels, catalogs, card files, 35mm slides dealing with the collections and history of the George M. Gray Museum and the Systematic Ecology Program.
New England; Cape Cod Bay (Mass.); Vineyard Sound; Gulf of Maine; USA; Massachusetts; Yale University
- 35mm Slide Collection, Series I
  - Equipment, Vessels, etc., 002024
    - Air boat & Scout. Air boat & Scout, Nov 1964; 002306
    - Air boat. Air boat, Nov 1964; 002305
    - Air boy. Air boy. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Sep 1966; 002358
    - Box dredge. Box dredge., May 1965; 002359
    - Box dredge. Box dredge., May 1965; 002360
    - Cayodetta. Cayodetta. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 1922; 002319
    - Epibenthic Trawl. Epibenthic Trawl, Nov 1965; 002361
    - Epibenthic Trawl. Epibenthic Trawl, Nov 1965; 002362
    - F/V Captain Bill. F/V Captain Bill, afterdeck., Feb 1966; 002318
    - Mini-dredge. Mini-dredge., Mar 1964; 002363
    - Mop Pickers. Mop Pickers., May 1965; 002412
    - Mop Pickers. Mop Pickers., May 1965; 002413
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge, May 1967; 002369
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge., Nov 1965; 002364
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge, Oct 1965; 002365
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge, Oct 1965; 002366
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge, Oct 1965; 002367
    - Naturalist Dredge. Naturalist Dredge, Oct 1965; 002368
    - Ocklemann Detritus Dredge. Ocklemann Detritus Dredge., Mar 1964; 002370
    - Otter Trawl. Otter Trawl towing frame., Feb 1967; 002371
    - Otter Trawl. Otter Trawl towing frame., Feb 1967; 002372
    - Otter Trawl. Otter Trawl, trailing for a set., Sep 1967; 002373
    - Photo Frame. Photo frame underwater., May 1965; 002374
    - Quahog Dredge. Quahog Dredge, modified. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1964; 002375
    - Quahog Dredge. Quahog Dredge, modified. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1964; 002376
    - Quahog Dredge. Quahog Dredge, modified. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1964; 002377
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill, artist's drawing., Jan 1966; 002346
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jan 1968; 002352
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill., Jul 1967; 002351
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Mar 1967; 002350
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill launching., Nov 1966; 002347
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill launching., Nov 1966; 002348
    - R/V A.E. Verrill. R/V A.E. Verrill launching., Nov 1966; 002349
    - R/V Albatross IV. R/V Albatross IV, just before overhaul. Massachusetts: Falmouth, Woods Hole., Jun 1970; 002310
    - R/V Albatross IV. R/V Albatross IV. Massachusetts: Falmouth, Woods Hole., 002309
    - R/V Atlantis & Reliance. R/V Atlantis & Reliance. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Aug 1951; 002315
    - R/V Atlantis II. R/V Atlantis II. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Aug 1966; 002317
    - R/V Atlantis II. R/V Atlantis II. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jul 1963; 002316
    - R/V Atlantis. R/V Atlantis, sailing day at WHOI Dock. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 1948; 002314
    - R/V Chain. R/V Chain. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Aug 1962; 002320
    - R/V Ciona. R/V Ciona, Feb 1967; 002322
    - R/V Ciona. R/V Ciona, Feb 1967; 002323
    - R/V Ciona. R/V Ciona, dive well and partitions. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jul 1964; 002321
    - R/V Dolphin & R/V Ciona. R/V Dolphin & R/V Ciona. Massachusetts: Woods Hole, Eel Pond., Jun 1967; 002328
    - R/V Dolphin & R/V Ciona. R/V Dolphin & R/V Ciona. Massachusetts: Woods Hole, Eel Pond., Feb 1965; 002326
    - R/V Dolphin and Limulus. R/V Dolphin and Limulus. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Sep 1955; 002335
    - R/V Dolphin, Nereis, etc. R/V Dolphin, Nereis, etc. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 1948; 002325
    - R/V Dolphin, R/V Ciona etc. R/V Dolphin, R/V Ciona, Limulus and Nereis. Massachusetts: Woods Hole, Eel Pond., Mar 1967; 002327
    - R/V Dolphin. R/V Dolphin, Mar 1966; 002329
    - R/V Dolphin. R/V Dolphin, Mar 1966; 002330
    - R/V Dolphin. R/V Dolphin, Mar 1966; 002331
    - R/V Dolphin. R/V Dolphin dredge operation., Nov 1962; 002404
    - R/V Gosnold. R/V Gosnold. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jun 1970; 002332
    - R/V Gosnold. R/V Gosnold. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Oct 1965; 002333
    - R/V Knorr. R/V Knorr. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jun 1970; 002334
    - R/V Melville. R/V Melville. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Oct 1969; 002336
    - Radar Reflector. Radar Reflector. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1965; 002378
    - Radar Reflector. Radar Reflector. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1965; 002379
    - Radar Reflector. Radar Reflector. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1965; 002380
    - Radar Reflector. Radar Reflector. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1965; 002381
    - Radar Reflector. Radar Reflector. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Nov 1965; 002382
    - Rock Dredge. Rock dredge., Sep 1964; 002383
    - Sample Washer. Sample washer., Nov 1965; 002384
    - Scout 800. Scout 800, 1966 model., Jan 1968; 002385
    - Shell Dredge. Shell dredge., Mar 1964; 002386
    - Shell Dredge. Shell dredge., Sep 1964; 002387
    - Shell Dredge. Shell dredge., Sep 1964; 002388
    - Simon Trip. Simon Trip., Jul 1967; 002405
    - Smith-McIntyre Grab and Shell Dredge. Smith-McIntyre Grab and Shell Dredge., Sep 1964; 002389
    - Smith-McIntyre Grab. Smith-McIntyre Grab., Sep 1965; 002390
    - Smith-McIntyre Grab. Smith-McIntyre Grab., Sep 1967; 002391
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002392
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002393
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002394
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002395
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002396
    - Squid Jigger. Squid Jigger., Jun 1967; 002397
    - Submersible Alvin II. Submersible Alvin II, 002312
    - Submersible Alvin II. Submersible Alvin II, 002313
    - Submersible Alvin. Submersible Alvin, ready for commissioning. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jun 1964; 002311
    - Subsurface Buoy. Subsurface Buoy, Dr. Dave Young., 02 Mar 1967; 002398
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Feb 1967; 002411
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Nov 1967; 002408
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Nov 1967; 002409
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Nov 1967; 002410
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Sep 1967; 002406
    - Trawl Catch. Trawl catch, Summers., Sep 1967; 002407
    - Trawl Wire Setup. trawl wire setup, Dr. Summers., Jun 1967; 002399
    - Trawl Wire Setup. trawl wire setup, Dr. Summers., Jun 1967; 002400
    - Turbojet. Turbojet. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Aug 1964; 002341
    - Turbojet. Turbojet. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jan 1965; 002342
    - Turbojet. Turbojet. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jan 1965; 002343
    - Turbojet. Turbojet. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jan 1965; 002344
    - Turbojet. Turbojet. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Jan 1965; 002345
    - USFC Phalarope. USFC Phalarope, 002339
    - USFC Stmr. Albatross. USFC Stmr. Albatross, 002307
    - USFC Stmr. Halcyon and USFC Stmr. Albatross. USFC Stmr. Halcyon and USFC Stmr. Albatross, 002308
    - Van Veen Grab. Van Veen Grab, closed., Mar 1964; 002401
    - Van Veen Grab. Van Veen Grab., May 1965; 002402
    - Van Veen Grab. Van Veen Grab., May 1965; 002403
    - Vessel Crawford. Vessel Crawford, Oct 1965; 002324
    - Vessel Mentor. Vessel Mentor. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 1948; 002337
    - Vessel Nereis. Vessel Nereis (Arbacia). Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Sep 1955; 002338
    - Vessel Thalassa. Vessel Thalassa, Aug 1962; 002340
    - Whaler & Scout. Whaler and scout. Massachusetts: Sandwich, Cape Cod Canal., Nov 1964; 002355
    - Whaler. Small whaler. Massachusetts: Sandwich, Cape Cod Canal., Nov 1964; 002354
    - Whaler. 16' whaler, 65hp. Massachusetts: Woods Hole, Eel Pond., Nov 1965; 002353
    - Yankee. Yankee and NY Yacht Club. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 1955; 002357
    - Yankee. Yankee. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., Aug 1952; 002356
  - Localities., 002023
    - Acorns. Acorns. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002085
    - Ammophila. Ammophila sp., Aug 1969; 002049
    - Ant Hill. Ant hill below high tide mark., Aug 1966; 002046
    - Barges. Old barges as groins in stormy fog. Massachusetts: Cuttyhunk., Aug 1963; 002083
    - Barnstable Dunes. Barnstable Dunes, Ammophila sp. and rainwater pool. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Aug 1952; 002054
    - Barnstable Dunes. West Barnstable Dunes, looking seaward. Massachusetts: Barnstable., 002055
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats. Massachusetts: Barnstable., 31 Mar 1967; 002063
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats. Massachusetts: Barnstable., 31 Mar 1967; 002064
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, looking SSW. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002056
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, Station A. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002057
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, Station C and station B. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002058
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, Station C. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002059
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, looking towards Station E. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002060
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, looking towards Station D & A. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002061
    - Barnstable Harbor. Barnstable Harbor flats, looking NNE. Massachusetts: Barnstable., Nov 1966; 002062
    - Beach Ice. Beach Ice, Feb 1966; 002038
    - Beach Ice. Beach Ice, Feb 1966; 002039
    - Beached Whale. Beached whale, female. 63'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Great Island, Jeremy Point., 02 Sep 1966; 002026
    - Beached Whale. Beached whale, female. 63'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Great Island, Jeremy Point., 02 Sep 1966; 002027
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002028
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002029
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002030
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002031
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002032
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002033
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002034
    - Beached Whale. Live beached whale, 61'. Massachusetts: Wellfleet, Mayo Beach., 12 Sep 1966; 002035
    - Biotic Census Quadrants. Biotic Census Quadrants, Jan 1970; 002036
    - Biotic Census Quadrants. Biotic Census Quadrants, Jan 1970; 002037
    - Bluegreen Algal Zone. Bluegreen Algal Zone. Gilbert Islands: Betio., 002040
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002066
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002067
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002068
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002069
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002070
    - Buzzards Bay Rocks. Buzzards Bay rocks. Massachusetts: Buzzards Bay., Aug 1965; 002071
    - Canada Geese. Canada geese. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002095
    - Canada Geese. Canada geese. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002096
    - Canada Geese. Canada geese. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002097
    - Canada Geese. Canada geese. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002098
    - Cape Cod. Aerial view of Cape Cod., 002050
    - Cuttyhunk Harbor. Cuttyhunk Harbor., Sep 1967; 002084
    - Eelgrass. Eelgrass, 1 m deep., Aug 1965; 002041
    - Eelgrass. Eelgrass, aquarium study., Aug 1965; 002042
    - Eelgrass. Eelgrass, aquarium study., Aug 1965; 002043
    - Eelgrass. Young eelgrass. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002086
    - Eelgrass. Young eelgrass, sta. 24. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002087
    - Falmouth. Leech Pond. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002189
    - Falmouth. Typha Pond, Sippewissett. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002190
    - Falmouth. Deep Pond, "Punch Bowl." Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002191
    - Falmouth. Pond near Jenkins Pond. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002192
    - Falmouth. Twin Ponds. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002193
    - Falmouth. Twin Ponds. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002194
    - Falmouth. Whittimore Pond, Sippewissett Road. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 1946; 002195
    - Falmouth. Wild Harbor oil spill. Massachusetts: Falmouth., Oct 1969; 002183
    - Falmouth. Wild Harbor oil spill. Massachusetts: Falmouth., Oct 1969; 002184
    - Falmouth. Wild Harbor oil spill. Massachusetts: Falmouth., Oct 1969; 002185
    - Falmouth. Wild Harbor oil spill. Massachusetts: Falmouth., Oct 1969; 002186
    - Falmouth. Wild Harbor oil spill. Massachusetts: Falmouth., Oct 1969; 002187
    - Falmouth. Chappaquoit Beach toward mainland. Massachusetts: Falmouth., 002188
    - Gull. Gull on beach., Jan 1966; 002045
    - Hadley Harbor. Northwest Gutter. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002088
    - Hadley Harbor. Northwest Gutter. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002089
    - Hadley Harbor. Northwest Gutter, 6'. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002090
    - Hadley Harbor. Shell and mud, 10'. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Jun 1965; 002092
    - Hadley Harbor. Rocky bottom in current. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Mar 1964; 002091
    - Hadley Harbor. Mud and rock, 20'. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., May 1965; 002094
    - Hadley Harbor. Shell bottom, 15'. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Oct 1965; 002093
    - Hydroelectric Plant. Hydroelectric plant. Massachusetts: Cape Cod Canal., Oct 1969; 002072
    - Jetty. Jetty. Massachusetts: Cape Cod., Jan 1966; 002052
    - Katydids. Pink katydids. Massachusetts: Woods Hole., 002053
    - Littorina. Littorina rock association. Massachusetts: Hadley Harbor., Aug 1965; 002119
    - Mallard Duck. Female mallard with young., Sep 1964; 002044
    - Martha's Vineyard. Aerial view. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., 1956; 002200
    - Martha's Vineyard. Gay Head Cliffs. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., 1958; 002201
    - Martha's Vineyard. Gay Head Cliffs. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Aug 1962; 002202
    - Martha's Vineyard. Gay Head Cliffs, no color. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jul 1965; 002203
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret nest. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002204
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret nest. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002205
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret nest. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002206
    - Martha's Vineyard. Norm Sinclair with heron chick. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002207
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret chicks. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002208
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret chicks. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002209
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret chicks. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002210
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret chicks. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002211
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret chicks. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002212
    - Martha's Vineyard. Snowy Egret. Menemsha. Massachusetts: Martha's Vineyard., Jun 1969; 002213
    - Mashpee. Ashumet Pond. Massachusetts: Mashpee., 1946; 002214
    - Mashpee. Ashumet Pond. Massachusetts: Mashpee., 1946; 002215
    - Mashpee. Luke Pond, Route 151. Massachusetts: Mashpee., 1946; 002216
    - Monomoy Island. Inward Point, Limulus trails. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 05 Jul 1967; 002223
    - Monomoy Island. Inward Point, Limulus trails. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 05 Jul 1967; 002224
    - Monomoy Island. Buildings and Lighthouse, Site #2. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002217
    - Monomoy Island. Buildings and Lighthouse, Site #2. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002218
    - Monomoy Island. Buildings and Lighthouse, Site #2. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002219
    - Monomoy Island. Buildings and Lighthouse, Site #2. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002220
    - Monomoy Island. Freshwater swale, area #1. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002221
    - Monomoy Island. Freshwater swale, area #1. Massachusetts: Monomoy Island., 26 Jul 1965; 002222
    - Monument Beach. Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002225
    - Monument Beach. Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002226
    - Monument Beach. Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002227
    - Monument Beach. Salt marsh, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002228
    - Monument Beach. Salicornia, shore, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002229
    - Monument Beach. Eelgrass community, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002230
    - Monument Beach. Eelgrass community, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002231
    - Monument Beach. Eelgrass community, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002232
    - Monument Beach. Eelgrass community, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002233
    - Monument Beach. Eelgrass community, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002234
    - Monument Beach. Rock pile, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002235
    - Monument Beach. Rock pile, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002236
    - Monument Beach. Rock pile, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002237
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002238
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002239
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002240
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002241
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002242
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002243
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002244
    - Monument Beach. Herring Gulls, Toby Island. Massachusetts: Bourne, Monument Beach., Aug 1965; 002245
    - Mount Desert Island. Zonation. Maine: Mount Desert Island, Manset., 002196
    - Mount Desert Island. Algal Zonation. Maine: Mount Desert Island, Manset., 002197
    - Mount Desert Island. Dr. Joly from Brazil. Maine: Mount Desert Island, Manset., 002198
    - Nashawena Island. Pond. Massachusetts: Nashawena Island., 1946; 002120
    - Nashawena Island. Pond. Massachusetts: Nashawena Island., 1946; 002121
    - Nashawena Island. Pond. Massachusetts: Nashawena Island., 1946; 002122
    - Nashawena Island. Pond. Massachusetts: Nashawena Island., 1946; 002123
    - Naushon Island. French watering place. Massachusetts: Naushon Island., Aug 1966; 002124
    - Naushon Island. Massachusetts: Naushon Island., Aug 1966; 002125
    - Nomans Land. Ocean side. Massachusetts: Nomans Land., 002246
    - Nomans Land. Botany Class. Massachusetts: Nomans Land., 002247
    - Nomans Land. Shoreline and driftwood. Massachusetts: Nomans Land., 002248
    - Nonamesset Island. Fawn Pond. Massachusetts: Nonamesset Island., 1946; 002127
    - Nonamesset Island. Deer Pond. Massachusetts: Nonamesset Island., 1946; 002128
    - Nonamesset Island. Deer Pond. Massachusetts: Nonamesset Island., 1946; 002129
    - Nonamesset Island. Sheep pen. Massachusetts: Nonamesset Island, Sep 1966; 002126
    - North Stonington, Maine. Ascophyllum. Maine: North Stonington., 002199
    - Orleans. Mudlfat, Town Cove. Massachusetts: Orleans, Aug 1965; 002249
    - Orleans. Mudlfat, Town Cove. Massachusetts: Orleans, Aug 1965; 002250
    - Orleans. Mudlfat, Town Cove. Massachusetts: Orleans, Aug 1965; 002251
    - Orleans. Mudlfat, Town Cove. Massachusetts: Orleans, Aug 1965; 002252
    - Orleans. Salt marsh, Rock Harbor Creek. Massachusetts: Orleans, Aug 1965; 002253
    - Penikese Island. Remains of leper cottages. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., 1959; 002130
    - Penikese Island. Agassiz memorial tablet. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., 1959; 002144
    - Penikese Island. From Agassiz tablet site.. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., 1975; 002131
    - Penikese Island. Queen Anne's Lace. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002134
    - Penikese Island. Morning Glory. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002135
    - Penikese Island. Caterpillar. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002136
    - Penikese Island. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002137
    - Penikese Island. Southwest Shore. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002139
    - Penikese Island. Northeast end. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002140
    - Penikese Island. Tub Pond. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002141
    - Penikese Island. Pond, southeast side. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002142
    - Penikese Island. Freshwater pond. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Aug 1967; 002143
    - Penikese Island. Algal zonation. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., Jul 1960; 002138
    - Penikese Island. From highland toward stone pier and R/V Dolphin. Massachusetts: Penikese Island., 002132